Maria Alejandra Escalante

Pagotá, Colombia mariaalejandraep@hotmail.com

Profile

Motivated and skillful undergraduate student pursuing a double major with experience in projects both as a leader and as a participant. Strong problem solving abilities and excellent at independent work. Bringing forth excellent organizational abilities, multitasking skills, and the drive to conquer goals. Adept at working well with others and committing myself as a positive team player. Currently working in machine learning, robotics, and web development.

Education

Aug 2016 — Jun 2021

Universidad de Los Andes

Bogotá

Bachelor Degree in Electronic Engineering

Jun 2017 — Dec 2021

Universidad de Los Andes

Bogotá

Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering

Nov 2019 — Mar 2020

Stanford University- Coursera

Machine Learning

Feb 2020 — Feb 2020

Universidad de Los Andes

Bogotá

Minor in German Language and Culture

Employment History

Aug 2018 — Dec 2018

Bogotá

Undergraduate Investigation Assistant in VR Lab at Universidad de Los Andes

Assisting Ph.D students in their investigations which included perception experiments and cross-platform homogeneity. I learned to create virtual reality environments using unity and VR equipment such as Gear VR, and I developed a personal project about perception in Virtual reality.

Jan 2020 — Present

Bogotá

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant in Web Development Class at Universidad de Los Andes

Assisting teacher and students in the development of web applications from design to deployment. This class is meant as an introduction to web development, and the tools and languages used are Netbeans, Angular, HTML, Typescript and Postman

Details

Calle 169b #75-73 casa 155

Bogotá, Colombia

3204501593

Date of birth

23/02/1998

Skills

Java

Python

ROS

Matlab & Simulink

Machine Learning

LabVIEW

SQL

HTML

Angular

Typescript

Linux OS

GitHub

Autodesk Inventor

Languages

Spanish

English

German

Jan 2018 — May 2018

Bogotá

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant in Algorithms and Programming Class at-Universidad de Los Andes

Teaching assistant in Algorithms and Programming level 2 class which included topics such as Interfaces, search algorithms, sorting algorithms, sockets, threads, simple and double linked lists and exception management. The class was taught in Java programming language, and my responsibilities included grading, and assisting the teacher during practical classes

Extra-curricular activities

Jun 2019 — Present

Undergraduate Electronic Engineer, ROBOCOL- Universidad de Los Andes

Robocol is a student initiative in Universidad de los Andes where students from mechanical engineering and electronic engineering are selected because of their skills to work in a prototype for a Mars Rover. We participated in the European Rover Challenge 2019 in Poland, and I took part in the creation and implementation of circuits and energy systems for controlling the traction, arm, cameras, and antennas

Ian 2019 — Present

Undergraduate Electronic Engineer, RAS-Universidad de Los Andes

RAS is a group focused in helping students design and implement automatic robots for competitions. I designed along with my team a mini sumo robot a competition in Argentina. The creation of the robot included PCB design, programming, and chasis design.

Jan 2020 — Present

Undergraduate Electronic Engineer

Machine learning project that goes from database creation to algorithm implementation. The project consist of creating a device for safety in intelligent cities.